# $\underset{1195 \text{ Stage Run Trail, Elizabeth CO}}{\textbf{DARREL RAY CLUTE, III}}_{1195 \text{ Stage Run Trail, Elizabeth CO}}$

95 STAGE RUN TRAIL, ELIZABETH CO 80107 — 517-618-1585 — DARREL@DARRELCLUTE.NET http://www.darrelclute.net/about/ — http://www.linkedin.com/in/darrelclute

# IT Infrastructure Architect

IT professional with over 10 years of experience in multiple roles. Excels in a dynamic environment with constant change. Prefers automation to manual repetition, and being a partner to the business instead of a simple services provider.

## Work Experience

03/2011 - Present — ViaSat Inc. El Camino Real, Carlsbad California 92009 760-476-2200

03/2011 - Present — Senior Network Engineer

- Focus on data center networking supporting Satellite Service Provider back office and operational support systems.
- Provide support and dissemination of knowledge to other engineers.
- Work with business owners on architecture, implementation and support of their applications, with a
  focus on network services.
- Work with other data center infrastructure teams toward the completion of projects our teams support.
- Provide knowledge transfer and augmentation to other infrastructure teams where own knowledge or experience surpasses that of the functional groups subject matter expertise.
- Encourage the adoption of Infrastructure as Code and Agile Operations methods, procedures, and tools, across functional groups.
- Implement and maintain server infrastructure supporting network operations, including:
  - SaltStack for configuration management.
  - Git for version control of configuration management data.
- Utilize configuration management for network supporting server infrastructure to automate the deployment of proxy white listing.

07/2010 - 01/2011 — Consumers Energy One Energy Plaza Drive, Jackson Michigan 49201 517-788-0550

07/2010 - 01/2011 — AMI Network Engineer

- Review and assess vendor equipment pertaining to Smart Grid Enablement such as:
  - Home Area Networking (HAN)
  - Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI)
- Evaluate wireless communications utilizing IEEE 802.15.4 (ZigBee) between AMI meters and HAN equipment such as:
  - Appliances
  - Home energy displays
  - Environmental controls
- Evaluate wireless communications of AMI meters in a mesh, along with transport of data back to head end.
- Evaluate functionality of vendor head end for their AMI solution.
- Manage VMware environment of approximately 200 virtual machines, containing internal servers and vendor environments.
- Enabled the Cisco Nexus 1000V virtual switch in a portion of the lab environment for demonstration purposes, with goal of enabling throughout the VMware infrastructure to provide greater network level control.

02/2009 - 07/2010 — Netarx, LLC (Acquired by Logicalis Group in July, 2011)

(Netarx acquired Analysts International VAR business unit in August 2009) 02/2009 - 07/2010 — Network Engineer

- On-demand work for customers, including:
  - Temporary staff augmentation
  - Break-fix resolution
- Project based work for customers, including:
  - Some pre-sales engineering

- DARREL@DARRELCLUTE.NET HTTP://www.darrelclute.net/about/ — HTTP://www.linkedin.com/in/darrelclute

- Production of implementation plans and detailed design documents
- Execution of implementation plans
- Perform assessments on customer infrastructure
  - Assess current state manually and with automated tools
  - Generate report for customer
  - Review report with customer staff
- Peer review of customer deliverables.
- Areas of expertise:
  - Network Management
  - Routing
  - Switching
  - Data Center Technologies
  - Security
  - Wireless
  - UNIX (HP-UX, Solaris)
  - Linux

03/2005 - 02/2009 — Liquid Web Inc. 4210 S Creyts Rd, Lansing Michigan 48917 800-580-4985

08/2008 - 02/2009 — System Administrator

- Technical support provided to web hosting customers, such as:
  - Hosting control panels (cPanel, Plesk)
  - Web servers (Apache, IIS)
  - Email services
  - Host firewalls (IPTables, Windows Firewall)

03/2005 - 08/2008 — Network Engineer

- Design, implement and maintain globally accessible web hosting network infrastructure.
  - Monitor and rebalanced outbound traffic flow over multiple carriers.
  - Manage IP allocations for use, and acquisitions through ARIN
  - Implement and maintain distributed authentication for network devices, utilizing:
    - \* Shrubbery Networks tac\_plus daemon
    - \* PAM
    - \* OpenLDAP
    - \* MIT Kerberos
  - Implement and maintain distributed syslog infrastructure.
  - Implement and maintain distributed SNMP trap and notification system.
- Design and maintain product development around network based services such as hardware firewalls and load balancers.
- Provide escalation support for suspected network related issues.
- Provide customer support on network based services.
- Provide training and documentation to engineering and support staff.

03/2003 - 03/2005 — Lansing State Journal 120 E Lenawee St, Lansing Michigan 48919 517-377-1000

03/2003 - 03/2005 — Information Technology Coordinator

- Project coordination for UNIX server infrastructure and core networking.
- Maintain server infrastructure on various platforms, such as:
  - Solaris
  - Linux
  - BSD
  - Windows
  - Mac OS 9 and 10

 $\underset{1195 \text{ Stage Run Trail, Elizabeth CO}}{\textbf{DARREL RAY CLUTE, III}}_{1195 \text{ Stage Run Trail, Elizabeth CO}}$ - DARREL@DARRELCLUTE.NET HTTP://www.barrelclute.net/about/ — http://www.linkedin.com/in/darrelclute

- Maintain core network infrastructure for both the LAN and WAN.
- Provide assistance to sister papers in the Michigan Synergy.
- Work with Gannett Corporate IT.
- Provide end user support to a mixed desktop environment.

09/2002 - 09/2006 — Computer Vision Networks (Dissolved)

09/2002 - 09/2006 — Partner and Chief Executive Officer

- Drafted and submitted original Articles of Incorporation.
- Drafted corporate by-laws adopted by shareholders.
- Responsible for coordinating and conducting all shareholder and board meetings.
- Maintained all financial records and corporate budgeting.
- Responsible for accounts payable and accounts receivable.
- Drafted, reviewed and approved all legal documents.
- Responsible for drafting all work authorizations and statements of work for customer projects.
- Performed warm sales calls in both an account manager and pre-sales engineer role.
- Reviewed and responded to all requests for proposal and quote.
- Maintained all vendor partnerships.

06/2002 - 03/2003 — **JAS Networks** 64 E Michigan Ave, Battle Creek Michigan 49017 269-288-5500

06/2002 - 03/2003 — Technical Support Specialist

- Provide technical support to customers both residential and commercial.
- Assist with management of servers, and network equipment.
- Assisted in the implementation and maintenance of OSPF and BGP routing architecture.
- Assisted in the maintenance of the ATM LANE environment which fed the Paradyne DSLAMs.
- Maintain database for trouble tickets both internal and with Ameritech.

06/2001 - 03/2002 — **Albion College** 611 East Porter, Albion, Michigan 49224 517-629-1000

06/2001 - 03/2002 — Network Assistant

• Provided assistance to the Network and System Administrators with various tasks.

### **Professional Certifications**

January 2, 2012 - Current Red Hat Certified Engineer, RHCE January 2, 2012 - Current Red Hat Certified System Administrator, RHCSA March 16, 2009 - March 16, 2012 Cisco Certified Network Associate, CCNA March 31, 2005 - Current Novell Certified Linux Professional January 29, 2005 - January 29, 2010 Linux Professional Institute Certified Level 1, LPIC-1 July 16, 2003 - July 16, 2006 Cisco Certified Network Professional, CCNP July 3, 2003 - July 16, 2006 Cisco Certified Design Professional, CCDP May 20, 2002 - July 16, 2006 Cisco Certified Design Associate, CCDA January 18, 2002 - July 16, 2006 Cisco Certified Network Associate, CCNA

### Education

2000 - 2002 — Calhoun Area Technology Center 475 E Roosevelt Ave, Battle Creek Michigan 49017 269-968-2271

Computer Networking — Cisco Network Academy Alumnus

1998 - 2002 — Albion Senior High School 225 Watson St, Albion Michigan 49224 517-629-9166

General Education — High School Dipoloma